

A2, Seethalakshmi Flats, No 32, Patel Street, Nehru Nagar, Chromepet, Chennai - 600044.

🛘 (+91) 9677059650 | 🔀 krishnan.gosakan@rutgers.edu | 🌴 krishnangosakan.github.io/KrishnanGosakan | 🖸 KrishnanGosakan

# **Summary**

A software engineer and researcher with 6 years of coding experience. My area of interest is in computer systems, ranging from compilers to system security. I am specializing on operating systems and computer architecture for my PhD research, with concentration in memory subsystem. I am switching to academia, after 6 years of professional experience, to pursue my PhD in computer science. I am a logical thinker and analytical in nature. I learn things quickly. I am looking forward for a research career, where I wish to improve user applications and operating systems for next generation computer architecture.

# Education

#### **Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey**

New Brunswick, New Jersey - 08901

Aug. 2022 - Present

DOCTORATE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

 Advisor: Prof Sudarsun Kannan • Lab: Rutgers Systems Research Lab

#### Sri Sivasubramaniya Nadar College of Engineering

Kalavakkam, Tamil Nadu - 603110

Aug. 2012 - July. 2016

**B.Tech in Information Technology** 

- Placed in First class with a CGPA of 7.153
- Final year project: Inter-video comparison for redundancy identification using python and mongodb database
- Project Advisor: Prof. E.M. Malathy
- · Implemented a File Management System using Front-end as java and Backend as oracle database as a mini academic project
- · Created a Banking Account Creation and Management software using Java as front-end and MySQL as back-end
- First prize in programming contest in SSN EEE symposium

## Smt Ramkuwar Devi Fomra Vivekananda Vidyalaya

Chromepet, Tamil Nadu - 600044

July. 2012

HIGHER SECONDARY, 12TH

- · Board: Tamil Nadu State Board
- Subjects: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Biology
- Scored **1121 marks** out of 1200 with an Engineering cut-off of **196.50**

#### Smt Ramkuwar Devi Fomra Vivekananda Vidyalaya

Chromepet, Tamil Nadu - 600044

SECONDARY SCHOOL, 10TH May. 2010

- Board: Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE)
- **Subjects**: Mathematics, Science, Social
- Scored CGPA of **9.6** out of 10
- Participated in various science quizzes
- Extracurricular Activities: Chess, Yoga

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

## **Zoho Corporation** MEMBER TECHNICAL STAFF

Chengalpattu, Tamil Nadu - 603202

Feb. 2017 - July. 2022

Aug. 2016 - Jan. 2017

• Worked as a C++ developer for Zoho Assist native Windows application and installer

- · Responsible for design, implementation, testing and customer support for Zoho Assist service and deployment components
- Module owner of Windows Deployment for Zoho Assist Unattended Installer
- Have experience in Microsoft **GPO and Intune** deployment technologies
- Worked on building an MSI based installer for Zoho Assist Unattended Support
- Developed a C# application for bulk deployment of Zoho Assist Unattended support InstallShield-based installer in domain or workgroup based windows network.
- Designed and developed a load testing framework for Zoho Assist
- Designed and developed version update system with failure detection using MD5 hash for Zoho Assist
- Reported **SQL injection** and **XSS** bugs in multiple Zoho products
- · Reported privilege escalation and injection based security issues in Zoho Assist as a part of HackFox internal security hackathon

Cognizant Siruseri, Tamil Nadu - 603103

- Trained on Mainframe Technology and Cobol programming language
- Worked on IBM Z mainframe systems

PROGRAMMER ANALYST TRAINEE

· Awarded as the Best Student of the Batch

AUGUST 21, 2022 KRISHNAN GOSAKAN · RÉSUMÉ